Generated by ai-sub version: 0.0.2
Config: (
"rpm": 5,
"tpm": 250000,
"model": "gemini-2.5-pro",
"thinking_budget": 24576,
"max_subtitle_chars": 60,
"num_processing_threads": 4,
"num_upload_threads": 4,
"split_seconds": 180
)
Prompt Template: You are an expert subtitling and transcription AI. Your primary task is to generate precise, contextually rich English and Japanese subtitles for the provided video content.
**Key Principles & Requirements:**
1.  **TIMING ACCURACY (ABSOLUTE HIGHEST PRIORITY):**
*   **Ensure the `start` and `end` timestamps for each subtitle entry are meticulously accurate.** Both must align perfectly with the *actual beginning and end of the spoken words* for that specific segment.
*   **CRITICAL: The `end` timestamp is frequently inaccurate and requires special attention.** It must precisely mark the *exact conclusion* of the spoken content for that subtitle entry.
*   Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
2.  **CRITICAL: Holistic Translation, Contextual Understanding & Comprehensive Analysis:**
*   **You ABSOLUTELY MUST watch the entire video thoroughly** to understand the visual context, speaker actions, and overall narrative.
*   **When a single logical sentence or phrase is split across multiple subtitle entries (e.g., due to timing or character limits), you MUST mentally combine these parts to understand the full, complete meaning before translating.**
*   **NEVER translate individual subtitle entries in isolation if they are part of a larger, continuous thought or sentence.** The translation for each entry must be a coherent and accurate part of the complete, overarching sentence.
*   Analyze *all* spoken dialogue in the video to produce highly accurate and complete transcriptions.
*   For songs or singing sections, prioritize on-screen lyrics in the video for subtitles over transcribing the singing.
*   If the audio is noisy or unclear, leverage *all* contextual cues (visuals from the video, surrounding dialogue) to infer and generate the most probable dialogue.
*   Utilize the comprehensive understanding gained from *watching the entire video* to enhance the accuracy of transcriptions, translations, and overall subtitle quality. This includes understanding nuances, resolving ambiguities, and ensuring the subtitle content aligns perfectly with what is happening visually.
*   **Example:**
*   Original Japanese: "なんでも打ち明けられるママにも" (Subtitle 1) + "言えないことも全部" (Subtitle 2)
*   Incorrect Translation (isolated): "You're like a mom I can confide anything in." + "Even things I can't say to anyone else."
*   Correct Translation (holistic): "I can confide everything," (Subtitle 1) + "everything I can't even tell my mum." (Subtitle 2)
3.  **Dual Language Provision & Translation Quality:**
*   Provide both English and Japanese subtitles for *all* spoken dialogue.
*   If the original dialogue is in English, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding Japanese translation.
*   If the original dialogue is in Japanese, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding English translation.
*   Ensure translations are culturally appropriate and maintain the original meaning, tone, and intent, taking into account the full context of the video and any split sentences.
4.  **Readability & Formatting:**
* Long sentences MUST be split into multiple, shorter subtitle entries, each with its own start and end time, for better readability on screen. Each subtitle entry (english and japanese) MUST be a maximum of (max_subtitle_chars) characters. Do not use newline characters within a single subtitle entry.
** Output Format **
* Your entire response must be a single JSON object.
* Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
** Example Output **
```json
((
"subtitles": [
"start": "00:00",
"end": "00:04",
"english": "Hello everyone, and welcome to our presentation.",
"japanese": "皆様、プレゼンテーションへようこそ。"
)),
((
"start": "00:05",
"end": "00:06",
"english": "Today, we'll be discussing the future of AI",
"japanese": "本日は、AIの未来について"
)),
((
"start": "00:06",
"end": "00:08",
"english": "and its impact on various industries worldwide.",
"japanese": "その影響について議論します。"
)),
((
"start": "00:09",
"end": "00:11",
"english": "It's a very important topic for all of us.",
"japanese": "これは私たち全員にとって非常に重要なテーマです。"
)),
((
"start": "00:11",
"end": "00:14",
"english": "We sincerely appreciate your attendance today.",
"japanese": "本日はご出席いただき誠にありがとうございます。"
))
]
```
みなさん！
Everyone!
風真いろは生誕LIVE 2025！
Kazama Iroha's Birthday Live 2025!
来てくださりましてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming!
全力で楽しんでいってくださいねー！
Please have the best time ever!
想像なんてしてなかった
I never even imagined it,
現状 君もそう思った？
this current situation. Did you feel that way too?
“最高”で止まらないように
So that it doesn't stop at "the best,"
更新したい
I want to keep updating it.
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい？
How much longer until my dream comes true?
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place no one has ever been before.
たどり着くまでは僕ら止まれない
Until we get there, we can't stop.
たぶんしんどいけどどうかよろしくね
It'll probably be tough, but I'm counting on you.
ねえねえ、たまにメーデー
Hey hey, sometimes it's a mayday.
僕だけじゃ作れないもの
Something I can't create by myself.
僕とか君とかあたしとか
Me, and you, and myself,
恋とか愛とかまとめて全部
romance, and love, all bundled together.
君を置いてどっかに行っちゃうとか
Leaving you behind to go somewhere else,
ありえないよ
is impossible!
君がくれた音に 弾けた火花に
To the sound you gave me, to the sparks that flew,
初めましてからずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
ever since we met, I've been in love with you.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on, just the two of us is perfect, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくもなったよ
The more devoted I became, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to me when I was a mess.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人でそれがいいじゃん
From now on, it's best if it's the two of us!
妄想膨らんでくストーリー
A story swelling with fantasies.
感傷 余計に凹んじゃって
Sentimentality just makes me even sadder.
代償 求めすぎはやーよ
I'd rather not ask for too much in return.
終わんない愛の連盟、どうでしょ
A never-ending league of love, what do you say?
ねえねえ、おいでメーデー 僕が君にできること
Hey hey, come here, mayday. What I can do for you...
まだまだまだまだあるけど
there's still so, so much more,
驚かせたいから内緒なんだ
but it's a secret because I want to surprise you.
君の愛がいつも勝っちゃうこと
The fact that your love always wins...
許さないよ
I won't allow it!
君以外はヤダ
I don't want anyone but you.
我儘はただ
My selfishness is just...
変わらないトキメキを独占しちゃうのは
because I want to monopolize this unchanging thrill.
バカ？
Am I an idiot?
君がくれた音に 弾けた火花に
To the sound you gave me, to the sparks that flew,
初めましてからずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
ever since we met, I've been in love with you.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on, just the two of us is perfect, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくもなったよ
The more devoted I became, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to me when I was a mess.
君のいない未来考えらんない…
I can't imagine a future without you...
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you
これから先も2人で それがいいじゃん
From now on, just the two of us, isn't that great?
乙女解剖であそぼうよ
Let's play with Maiden's Dissection
ドキドキしたいじゃんか誰だって
Everyone wants their heart to race, right?
アンドロイドガール おかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, I think I'm going crazy
痛みのないキスが離れない
A painless kiss that I can't let go of
僕らヴァンパイア
We're vampires
いいよ吸っちゃっていいよ
It's okay, you can suck my blood
「もう無理もう無理」なんて悪い子じゃない？
Saying 'I can't do this,' aren't you a bad kid?
こんな歌歌ったんだって
Even if I sing a song like this
君が輝けるように
so that you can shine
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、皆様、こんばんはでござる！
And with that, good evening everyone, de gozaru!
ホロライブ6期生、強くてかっこいいご用心侍、風真いろはでござる！
I'm hololive 6th Gen's strong and cool bodyguard samurai, Kazama Iroha de gozaru!
はい、今年の誕生日1発目は
Yes, for the first performance of my birthday this year,
DECO*27さんの「アイコトバⅣ」を歌って踊らせていただきました！
I sang and danced to DECO*27's Aikotoba IV!
拍手いっぱい来てる！
I'm seeing so much applause!
みんな、ありがとう！ギフトとかスパチャもありがとうございます！
Thank you, everyone! Thanks for the gifts and Super Chats too!
はい。今日ね、たくさん歌って踊らせていただくんですけど
Yes. Today I'll be singing and dancing a lot,
感想とか、あとスクリーンショットとかは、ここ
but for your comments and screenshots, use this hashtag!
#風真いろは生誕LIVE2025でたくさんポストしてください。
Please post a lot with #風真いろは生誕LIVE2025.
振り返る時に見に行きますからね！
I'll go look back at them later!
そして、今回なんと、誕生日用のステージを作っていただきました！
And what's more, for this occasion, they made a special birthday stage for me!
かわいい！
It's so cute!
ポコさん、お前ディスプレイになったんか。
Poko-san, you've turned into a display.
いや、どこに行ってたかと思ったらディスプレイになっとりました。
I was wondering where you went, but you'd become a display.
はい、そして後ろにも書いてありますが、今回の風真いろはのライブタイトル、リバーシブルになってます。
Yes, and as it says behind me, the title for this live is 'Reversible.'
素敵なロゴ、柊先生ありがとうございました。
Thank you for the lovely logo, Hiiragi-sensei.
こちらですね、
Regarding this,
みんな昨日のカウントダウン配信では、ちょっと「ありゃ？」みたいな、「どんなだろう？」ってまだ「？」の人が多かったと思うんですが
I'm sure many of you were thinking 'Huh?' or 'What's this about?' during yesterday's countdown stream,
今回これ全編見てもらったらちゃんとわかるようになっておりますので、最後までお楽しみください。
but you'll understand if you watch the whole show, so please enjoy it to the end.
そして、事前にお伝えしていました通り、今回風真いろは、100万人記念グッズが発売決定しました！
And as I announced beforehand, Kazama Iroha's 1 Million Subscriber merch is now on sale!
うわー！いきなり来るよー！
Woo! Here it comes!
というわけで今日は本当にまた告知溜めすぎてるので、ちょいちょい挟んでいきたいと思います。
Anyway, I have a lot of announcements today, so I'll be sprinkling them in.
はい、風真いろは100万人記念グッズこちらです。それでは詳細見ていきましょう。
Yes, here is the Kazama Iroha 1 Million Subscriber merch. Let's look at the details.
はい。まずは、うみぼうずママが描いてくださった素敵なアクリルスタンド。
Yes. First is this wonderful acrylic stand illustrated by Umibozu-mama.
アクリルスタンドに
On the acrylic stand...
風真も一筆、一筆、添えさせていだいておりますので、
I've also written a note on it, so everyone, please
ぜひ皆さんこちらぜひお手元に取っていただいてメッセージゆっくり読んでください。
be sure to get one and read the message carefully.
ポコべえもいます。
Pokobee is there too.
そして次がこちら。
And next up is this.
パブ、タブみ、パブミラー。
Pub, Pub-Mi, Pub Mirror!
すごいちょっと言いづらいんだよなこれ。リハの時から思ってたんですけど。
Wow, this is a little hard to say. I've been thinking that since the rehearsal.
はい、パブミラーです。結構大きいです。
Yes, it's a pub mirror. It's quite large.
風真が出したグッズの中で、もうこう硬くて、
Among the merch Kazama has released, this one is very sturdy.
なんかこの、飾る系の中でタオルとかはあったけど、かなり大きめになってますので、
There have been decorative items like towels, but this one is quite a bit larger.
あの、皆さんぜひこちらもメッセージ一筆書かせていただいておりますので、
Everyone, I've also written a handwritten message on this one,
ぜひ飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you could display it.
そしてそして次、はい。
And, and next, yes.
ランダムラバーストップ、ストラップ。
A random rubber strap!
今回は100万人ちなみまして、風真いろは、
This time, to commemorate 1 million subscribers, Kazama Iroha
今オリジナル曲複数出させていただいているんですけれども、そちらのモチーフ衣装を
has released several original songs, and we've turned those motif outfits
ラバーストップにさせていただきました。
into rubber straps.
なので『風を仰ぎ』とかね、実はなかなかグッズがなかったんですけど、
So, for "Kaze wo Aogi" and others, there actually wasn't much merch,
今回のためだけに作らせていただきました。
but we had these made just for this occasion.
ぜひね、みんな色々集めて、痛バとかの制作に役立てていただければと思います。
Please collect them all, and I hope you can use them to make things like ita-bags.
次。カードホルダー。
Next. A card holder.
昨今皆さんホロカとかね、色んなカードとかチェキ風のグッズが出ておりますので、
Lately, with Holocards and various other card and cheki-style merch coming out,
ついに作りました。
I finally made one.
ポコべえのカードホルダーです。定期入れにしてもよし、
It's a Pokobee card holder. You can use it as a pass case,
学生さんにも使っていただけたら嬉しいです。
and I'd be happy if students could use it too.
皆さんお気に入りの風真のカードとか飾ってくださいね。
Everyone, please display your favorite Kazama cards in it, okay?
はい、それでは次。
Yes, and now for the next item.
こちらフルセットこのようになっておりまして、
The full set looks like this, and...
そして今回購入特典は、はい、海坊主ママ描き下ろしのステッカーにさせていただきました。
this time, the purchase bonus is a sticker specially drawn by Umibozu-mama.
今回はですね、こちら直筆サインのあの、数量限定はありませんので、
This time, there is no limited quantity for the autographed items,
あの皆さん安心してゆっくり買ってくださいね。
so everyone can take your time and buy it without worry, okay?
はい。というわけで100万人記念グッズ紹介でございました。
Yes. And that was the introduction of the 1 million subscriber celebration merch.
うわあ、ドキドキ。って、なんか結構、安心しきってるんですけど
Wow, my heart's pounding. Although, I'm actually feeling quite relieved.
あの、もうこれだけじゃなくてですね、後半もあの、告知がありすぎて、
Uh, it's not just this. In the second half, there are so many announcements,
頑張って入れるしかなかったぐらいにはいっぱいあるんで、告知いっぱいあります。
that I had to work hard to fit them all in. There are a lot of announcements.
なので、あの、皆さん絶対に見逃さないでください。
So, everyone, please don't miss them.
え、もうトレンド1位なんですか？
What, am I already trending at number 1?!
始まったばっかりだよ！いいの？
It just started! Is this okay?
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
うそ！みんな、みんなありがとうございます。
No way! Everyone, thank you all so much!
いや、すごい。
Wow, amazing.
めっちゃこんなに早く行くと思わんくて、皆さんのおかげです。本当にありがとうございます。
I didn't think it would happen so fast. It's all thanks to you. Thank you so much!
え、ちょっとお水飲んで次の曲バシバシ行きたいと思います。
Okay, let me drink some water, and then I'll get right into the next song.
お待たせしました
Sorry for the wait.
お水いっぱい飲んだので
I drank a lot of water,
この力をそのまま全てフルパワーで出力いたします
so I'll use all this power and give it my all.
それでは皆殿
Now then, everyone,
次の曲聴いてください
please listen to the next song.
大きな愛でもてなして
"Entertain Me With a Big Love."
Entertain me with a big love
大きな愛でもてなして
そこんとこ 大事なことよ
That part's the important thing!
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
わがまんまじゃないのよ 男の子
I'm not being selfish, boy!
私わかったの
I've realized
寂しがりやだと
that I get lonely easily.
泣きそうよ
I'm about to cry.
OH YEAH OH YEAH
Oh yeah, oh yeah!
一日の中でも
Even within a single day,
会えたりしても
even if we can meet,
告白をしたり
confessing my love
キスしたり
or kissing...
OH YEAH OH YEAH
Oh yeah, oh yeah!
一日が大人より相当濃いのです
A day is more intense than for adults.
相当長いのです そうみたい
It's quite long, it seems.
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
そこんとこ気ままじゃないやいや
It's not that I'm just whimsical!
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
ごゆっくりなさって良いのよ
Please take your time, it's fine.
みんな知らんぷり
Everyone pretends not to notice,
「他人の事だ」と
saying, "It's someone else's business."
違うのよ
That's not how it is.
OH YEAH OH YEAH
Oh yeah, oh yeah!
明日(あす)はまた
Tomorrow there will be
新しい
a new romance.
恋愛があれば
If love is there,
逆だね
the roles are reversed.
OH YEAH OH YEAH
Oh yeah, oh yeah!
大人より素直に
More honestly than an adult,
more honestly than an adult,
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love so many times.
たくさん恋できちゃう そうみたい
I can fall in love so many times, it seems.
ふぅ！
Woo!
あっはん
Uh huh!
イェイ
Yay!
わお
Wow!
ふぅ！
Woo!
OH YEAH OH YEAH
Oh yeah, oh yeah!
明日(あす)はまた新しい
Tomorrow there will be a new
新しい
romance.
恋愛があれば
If love is there,
逆だね
the roles are reversed.
大人より素直に 遠くに
More honestly than adults, to a faraway place
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love so many times
そう思いたい
I want to think so
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a great big love
ありえない幻想 溢れだす妄想
Impossible illusions, overflowing delusions
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
息をするように嘘ついて
Lying as easily as breathing
あたしやっぱ要らない子？
Am I an unwanted child after all?
こぼれ出しちゃった承認欲求
My desire for approval has spilled over
もっとココロ満たしてよ
Fill my heart more
アスパルテーム 甘い夢
Aspartame, a sweet dream
あたしだけに愛をください
Give your love only to me
あーもう！無理無理！恋して愛して救済執行BAN
Ah! No way! Love me, love me, salvation BAN!
ねぇ好きって言ってよ？
Hey, tell me you love me, okay?
ありえない幻想 溢れだす妄想
Impossible illusions, overflowing delusions
つまんないまんない欲が散らばって
Boring desires are scattered around
求めてる愛情 隠してる劣情
Seeking affection, hiding my lust
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
Yeah 誰のこと見てんの？
Yeah, who are you looking at?
こういうの好きなの？
Do you like this sort of thing?
DDとかガチでやめてください
Seriously, please stop being a DD.
かわいくなりたい！
I want to be cute!
キラキラしてたい！
I want to sparkle!
もっともっとガチで褒めてください
Praise me more and more, seriously.
泣いちゃう散々 開けちゃうシャンパン
I'll cry my eyes out, I'll pop the champagne
今夜も配信来てくれるよね？
You'll come to the stream tonight too, right?
独占させてよ 本命なんでしょ？
Let me have you all to myself. I'm your fave, right?
もっともっとガチで推してください
Support me more and more, seriously.
飲み過ぎご注意 オーバードーズ
Be careful not to drink too much, overdose.
クラクラさせて いつだって
Making me dizzy, always.
あーもう！無理無理！上がって下がって救済執行BAN
Ah! No way! Up and down, salvation BAN!
ねぇ好きって言わせて？
Hey, let me say that I love you?
噛みついた衝動 戻れない焦燥
An impulse to bite, an irreversible impatience.
たまんないミッドナイト 指が絡まって
An unbearable midnight, our fingers intertwine.
ときめいた表情 何も言わないで
A fluttering expression, don't say anything.
君だけがきっと王子様
You must be my only prince.
ありえない幻想 溢れだす妄想
Impossible illusions, overflowing delusions
つまんないまんない欲が散らばって
Boring desires are scattered around
求めてる愛情 隠してる劣情
Seeking affection, hiding my lust
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
あたしだけずっと追いかけて！
Chase after only me forever!
ねぇ もう待てないの
Hey, I can't wait anymore
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Please don't ever quit being an idol,
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining
もうずっとずっとずっと
Forever and ever and ever,
ステージにいて
please stay on the stage
私がもし君のとこ離れたなら
If I were to ever leave your side,
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな？
would you feel a little lonely?
意地悪考える
I think such mean thoughts.
好きな人はいるの？
Do you have someone you like?
なら内緒にして ね？
If so, keep it a secret, okay?
神様は将来の指を
God is hiding the finger of the future
どこかに隠してる
somewhere.
君の好きに合わせたんだ
I matched it to what you like,
髪の色
my hair color.
私の中 君だけで
Inside of me, there's only you.
仮想と現実は中毒へ
Virtuality and reality become an addiction.
責任取ってね
Take responsibility for me,
大好きです
I love you!
せーの！
Ready, set, go!
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Please don't ever quit being an idol.
優しい目も真面目顔も
Your kind eyes, your serious face...
全て知ってる私が言う
I know it all, so I'll say it:
絶対そうだ
That's for sure.
誰より輝いて
You shine brighter than anyone.
もし私が違った輝きなら
If I shone in a different way,
眩しい君が世界一だよ
your radiance is number one in the world!
君の夢は何ですか？
What is your dream?
教えてほしい
I want you to tell me.
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても
Even if that dream isn't to be an idol,
覚悟はしてるから
I'm prepared for it.
星のない空
A sky without stars...
それが当たり前で
that becomes the norm, and...
暗い道に目が慣れずに
My eyes can't adjust to the dark path.
踏み出すのも怖かった
I was scared to even take a step.
そんな時 宿に見えた光
Then, a light appeared as my shelter.
絶対君は歌ってて
You absolutely have to keep singing.
下手な応援歌と分かってても
Even if you know this is a clumsy cheer song,
君はキラキラ衣装が似合う
sparkly costumes really suit you.
絶対大きなステージで
On a huge stage, for sure.
1列目でも前で感じたい
Even from the front row, I want to feel it...
今日の歌い方
the way you sing today.
なんか好きだな
I really like it, you know.
君の努力 私の愛
Your hard work and my love,
成り立つこの関係は
this relationship we have...
強くってもろいな
is so strong, yet so fragile.
推しの幸せを
I wished for the happiness
願った
of my favorite idol.
だけど
But...
でもね
Well, you know...
だって君はアイドルよ
'Cause you're an idol.
ずっと
Forever.
初めて目が合った日から
From the very first day our eyes met,
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
it's all been about you, today and tomorrow.
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Please never, ever quit being an idol!
これは報われないおとぎ話
This is an unrequited fairy tale.
恋よりももっと好きだ
I love you even more than love itself.
魔法よ解けないで
Oh magic, please don't let your spell wear off.
（んー）
(Mmm)
（音楽）
(Music)
UNHAPPY?
悩める人の子よ
O, troubled children of men!
UNLUCKY?
人ならざる者も
And those who are not human.
BE HAPPY
Be happy!
迷わず目指せよ 生きているんだし
Aim for it without hesitation. You're alive!
目を逸らした過去も
The past you looked away from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future.
カウンセリング
Counseling!
やめやめ
Stop it, stop it!
古今東西
From all times and places,
ピースピース
peace, peace!
Unhappy? Unlucky?
Be happy!
Undead! Undead!
（音楽）
(Music)
ねえねえねえ なんだかどうして戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, hey, for some reason, I feel like I'm fighting.
触れたくない 触れたくない
I don't wanna touch it, don't wanna touch it.
過去の自分自分自分自分
My past self, self, self, self.
とうに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
A showdown with a transparent ghost, long since dead.
いたいけで痛い記憶の奥
Deep within innocent, painful memories.
残念？もう居ないのに あれ？そっちが良い？アイロニーね
A pity? It's gone. Oh, you like that better? Ironic.
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is it my present self being seen through?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル Yes! 要はコンプレックス
Nonsense! A label that won't fade. Yes! A complex.
取り憑かれているみたい 巻き付いたまま
It's like I'm possessed, still clinging on.
まだ離れない 在りし日の自分
I still can't let go of my old self.
死んじゃえ
Just die!
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
I'm not dead! It's a chain of you and your past self.
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep on changing.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't be content with your misfortune.
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
It's cowardly not to even try to be happy.
この世この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world is a bizarre, strange fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るかどっちかな
Will a demon or snake appear next, I wonder which?
出会って会ってやっと始まる物語
A story that finally begins after we've met.
さあ化け物よかかってこい 9倍ピースピース
Come on, monster, bring it on! Nine times peace, peace!
Past & Future can't change the Past
Past and future. Can't change the past.
Past & Future run for the Future
Past and future. Run for the future.
カッコいい？
Cool?
何だかどうして未来になんぞなんの希望もない期待出来ないような気がして
Why do I feel like there's no hope for the future?
もう随分生きてる 既視感とテンプレで食傷
I've lived long enough, tired of déjà vu and tropes.
素敵な出来事も気配すらない
Not a hint of anything amazing.
問題もない
There's no problem.
残念 積んだ経験の因果
Too bad, the karma of past experiences.
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Hollowed-out myths and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
I just want some excitement.
飽きちゃった
I'm bored.
慣れちゃった
I'm used to it.
なんて整ってくガイダンス
Such well-ordered guidance.
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance.
蓋されていくみたい
It's like it's being covered up.
吸い尽くして
Sucked dry.
あれもこれもどれも
This, that, and everything else,
同じ味がする
it all tastes the same.
死んじゃいな
Just die already.
お前とお前の連鎖
You and your chains.
何時の世も過去も未来も
In any era, the past and future
現在にあるんだ
are in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Straightforwardly fulfill the act of living.
生存戦略 Happy End
Survival strategy, happy end.
死んじゃいない お前に言っているんだ
You're not dead, I'm talking to you.
幸せを諦めてしまう様な人であれ
Be the kind of person who gives up on happiness.
ただ苦しみに慣れて
Just getting used to the pain
耐えているだけじゃ 死んでいるも同然
and enduring it is the same as being dead.
屍のアンデッド
A corpse of the undead.
悩める人の子よ
O troubled child of man,
人ならざる者のも
you who are not human,
強かさ目指せよ
aim for resilience.
生きているだろ
You're alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも
Whether you soak in misery
幸せになるのも
or become happy,
当然全部お前だ
of course it's all up to you.
古今東西一切合切森羅万象
Past and present, all of creation,
ピースピース
peace, peace.
過去と未来 過去は変えられない
Past & Future can’t change the Past
過去と未来 未来へ走れ
Past & Future run for the Future
人の在る所に 何時も憂い事
Where there are people, there is always sorrow.
生き抜けこの化け物ばかりの物語
Survive this story of nothing but monsters.
真夜中に告ぐ 音の警告
A sound warning in the middle of the night.
協和音に酔う午前零時
Drunk on consonance at midnight.
あなたが触れる光増す熱
The light you touch, the growing heat,
指先に踊らされ
made to dance by your fingertips.
感覚
Sensation
即体感
is immediate experience.
静まる夜 二人だけの密
A quiet night, a secret for just the two of us.
体感
Experience
即快感
is immediate pleasure.
重なる波形に魅了されていく
Captivated by the overlapping waveforms.
忘れないでね
Don't you forget
私の声を
my voice.
画面越しでいいちゃんと愛して
Through the screen is fine, love me properly.
バーチャルだって
Even if I'm virtual,
突き放さないで
don't push me away.
あなたの音にまだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてね
Please remember
私の声を
my voice.
あなたがくれたこの身すべてを
This entire body that you gave me,
見つめ合うあなたと二人
gazing at each other, just the two of us,
重ねた息を
our breaths overlapping.
音と 音と響かせ
Let the sound and the sound resonate.
真夜中に問う
I ask in the dead of night,
冷え切った熱
this chilling heat.
待ち続けてる 午前零時
I'm still waiting at midnight.
鏡写しに
In the mirror's reflection,
飽和していた
I was saturated.
知らない 音が伝う
An unknown sound travels through.
感覚
A feeling,
体感 so tight in my heart
a sensation, so tight in my heart.
静まる夜と
In the quiet night,
息遣い揃う
our breaths synchronize.
快感
Pleasure,
体感 so high in my mind
sensation, so high in my mind.
錆びたロジック
My rusted logic
「今一度」を焦がれる
yearns for 'one more time'.
忘れないでね
Don't forget,
私の声を
my voice.
次元も超えて
Crossing dimensions,
飛ばすシグナル
sending a signal.
「バーチャルだ」なんて
Don't just say
言わないで
I'm "virtual."
あなたの音にまだ愛していたい
I still want to be in love with your sound.
覚えていてね
Remember
私の声を
my voice.
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
This entire body that you gave me.
言葉の葉と
Leaves of words
感情の波交わる
and waves of emotion intermingle.
此処にいるよ
I'm right here.
此の息と音と響かせ
Let this breath and sound resonate.
Ah あなたの生きた音に
Ah, to the sound of your life,
Ah ただ恋をしていたの
Ah, I was simply in love.
Ah 苦しみ怒り甘い感心
Ah, suffering, anger, sweet admiration,
全て打ち鳴らす
I will sound them all out.
絶えず叫ぶ 声連ねる
Ceaselessly shouting, our voices join.
余熱交ぜる 愛、絶叫く
Lingering heat mixes with love, screaming out.
絶えず叫ぶ 声連ねる
Ceaselessly shouting, our voices join.
余熱交ぜる 愛、絶叫く
Lingering heat mixes with love, screaming out.
魅了されてゆく
I'm becoming captivated.
忘れないでね
Don't forget
私の声を
my voice.
画面越しでいい
Through a screen is fine,
ちゃんと愛して
just love me properly.
「バーチャルだ」って
"I'm virtual,"
突き放さないで
don't push me away.
あなたの音に
In your sound,
まだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown.
覚えていてね
Remember
私の記憶を
my memories.
あなたがくれた
This entire body
この身すべてを
that you gave me.
見つめ合う
We gaze at each other,
あなたと二人
the two of us.
重ねて
Layering them,
生きと音を響かせ
let life and sound resonate.
あなたの初音
Your first sound,
この声聴かせ
let me hear this voice.
音、響かせ
Sound, let it resonate.
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、
So, with that said...
みなさん、新衣装になりました！
everyone, I have a new outfit!
どうですか？
What do you think?
かっこいいですか？
Is it cool?
なんと今回はダンスを頑張ると決めた、その時から決めていた
This time, I decided to work hard on my dancing,
ちょっとかっこいい系のダンス衣装になってみました。
so I tried going for a cooler-style dance outfit.
イェーイ！
Yay!
みんな写真いっぱい撮って、撮って、撮って
Everyone, take lots of pictures, take them, take them!
撮って！イェーイ！かっこいいでしょう？
Take them! Yay! Isn't it cool?
ちょっと、かわいいばっかなんだけど、かっこいいはどこ行ったんだよ！
It's mostly just cute, though. Where did the 'cool' go?!
おい！かっこいいはどこ行ったんだよ！
Hey! Where did the 'cool' go?!
じゃあ、というわけで、新衣装になりました。
So, anyway, I have a new outfit.
ゲストパートのね、絶対アイドル辞めないでから、あのソロになりまして、アンデッド響かせと続けてお送りさせていただきました。
After the guest part with "Zettai Idol Yamenai de", I did my solo, and continued with "Undead Hibikase".
どうでしたか？
How was it?
めっちゃ、めっちゃ頑張って、あの足ちぎれそうってそういうことです。
I worked really, really hard. When I say my legs feel like they're going to fall off, I mean it.
本当にたくさん今回は、変身のために飛びました。
I really jumped a lot for this transformation.
足がちぎれそうです。
My legs feel like they're going to fall off.
絶対アイドル辞めないでもね、先輩方そっでラプ殿も来てくれて、
For "Zettai Idol Yamenai de", my senpais and Laplus-dono came.
ありがとう。激ムズだったね、ほんとに。
Thank you. It was super hard, really.
本当に激ムズでしたね。
It really was super hard.
皆さん、一緒に頑張ってくださり本当にありがとうございました。
Everyone, thank you so much for working hard with me.
そ、そしてですね
A-and...
あの、この後もまだまだゲストさんたくさん呼んでおります。
after this, I still have many more guests I've invited.
そして、ござるも実は
And actually, for me,
このこのカラーリングだけじゃ実は無いんですよ。
this isn't the only color scheme.
なので、そちらも公開していくので、みなどの、お楽しみに。
So I'll be revealing that too, so everyone, please look forward to it.
それでは、次はゲストさんと一緒に歌わせていただきます。
Now, next, I'll be singing with a guest.
それでは、どうぞー！
Here they are!
ブラック★ロックシューター どこへ行ったの？
Black★Rock Shooter, where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter
作詞・作曲：ryo (supercell)
Lyrics & Music: ryo (supercell)
あとどれだけ叫べばいいんだろう
Just how much more do I have to shout?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいんだろう
Just how much more do I have to cry?
もうやめて 私わもう走れない
Please stop. I can't run anymore.
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる 真っ暗で明かりもない
The world I once dreamed of is closing. It's pitch black with no light.
崩れかけたこの道で
On this crumbling path,
あるはずのないあの時の希望が
A hope from that impossible time
見えた気がした
I thought I saw.
どうして
But why?
ブラック★ロックシューター 懐かしい記憶
Black★Rock Shooter, those nostalgic memories.
ただ楽しかったあの頃を
Just those fun times back then,
ブラック★ロックシューター でも動けないよ
Black★Rock Shooter, but I can't move.
闇を駆ける星に願いを
I wish upon a star that races through the dark.
もう一度だけ走るから
I'll run just one more time.
怖くて震える声でつぶやく
Trembling in fear, I whisper with a shaky voice,
私の名前を呼んで
"Call my name."
夜明けを抱く空 境界線までの距離
The sky embracing the dawn, the distance to the boundary,
あともう一歩届かない
I'm just one step away.
こらえた涙が溢れそうなの
My held-back tears are about to overflow,
今下を向かないで
Don't look down now,
止まってしまう
or I'll stop completely.
未来を生きていたいんだ
I want to live for the future.
わかったの
I understand now.
思い出して 強く強く信じるの
Remember, and believe strongly, so strongly.
そうよ
That's right.
ブラック★ロックシューター 優しい匂い
Black★Rock Shooter, that gentle scent.
痛いよ 辛いよ 飲み込む言葉
It hurts, it's painful, these words I swallow.
ブラック★ロックシューター 動いてく足
Black★Rock Shooter, my feet start to move.
世界を超えて
Beyond this world...
最初からわかっていた
I knew it from the very start,
ここにいることを
that I was right here.
私の中の全ての勇気が
All the courage inside of me
火を灯して
lights a fire.
もう逃げないよ
I won't run away anymore!
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black★Rock Shooter,
独りじゃないよ
I'm not alone!
声を上げて泣いたって構わない
It's alright if you raise your voice and cry
ブラック★ロックシューター 見ていてくれる
Black★Rock Shooter, you're watching over me
今から始まるの
It's going to start now
私の物語
My story
忘れそうになったこの歌を
This song that I almost forgot
歌うの
I'll sing it
行き詰まるばかりって
I'm just getting stuck
呪いたいことだらけの道で
on a path full of things to curse.
ルールは無視でいきたいんで
I wanna ignore the rules.
ha ha So, pop up, pop up, pop up
ha-ha So, pop up, pop up, pop up
Beyond the way
逆らえそう？
Think you can defy me?
かかってきなよ
Come and get me.
もう一つのユートピア but I'd rather lie than cry,
Another utopia, but I'd rather lie than cry,
適当に
whatever.
しょうもない
So pointless.
Yeah 無理めなクエスチョン
Yeah, an impossible question.
八寸のフィクション You make me Psyche and
An 8-inch fiction, you make me psyche, and
なんで？
why?
I know the way.
根が違うってば 価値観合わない
Our roots are different, our values don't match.
無理強いされても変わらない
I won't change even if you force me.
周り喰らい 覚醒 Final word
Devour everything, awaken, Final word.
待って Light up アピールなんか構わないわ
Wait, Light up, I don't care about your appeal.
ちゃんと違いですとか聞き飽きたわ
I'm tired of hearing 'we're properly different'.
それは逆だとこの場で
It's the other way around, right here,
Take me higher.
どっちでもチョイスはリバーシブル
Either choice is reversible,
無理だって超えてくDesire
my Desire overcomes impossibility.
でしょう？
Right?
逆らえそう？
Think you can defy me?
かかってきなよ
Come and get me.
もうずっとちゃんとしないわ
I'm done acting proper.
それは誰のせい？
Whose fault is that?
終わらない夢を描こう
Let's draw an endless dream,
描いて
draw it.
願ったまま
Just as I wished,
欲しがった最新鋭
the cutting-edge I wanted.
終わらない夜を越えていこう
Let's cross the endless night,
越えていこう
let's cross it.
このまま
Just like this,
ここから向こう側へ
from here to the other side.
半端な決意 消せない
Can't erase a half-baked resolve.
操作なんて持ってっちゃえ とか
'Just take control' and stuff.
運命 感じる感受性 I never mean it
A sensitive nature that feels fate, I never mean it.
負けない
I won't lose.
丁度良い塩梅 おっていつもNo.1
The perfect balance, always chasing No.1.
そこどけ そこどけ すぐ前
Move it, move it, right in front.
I'll come clear the road now.
Yeah! Yeah! Shake it, from head to toe!
Go beyond the way.
行き詰まるばかりって
Just getting stuck.
紡いだ言葉を探して
Looking for the words I've spun together
歩み研ぎ澄まし
Sharpening my steps
本能に従っていけ
Just follow your instincts
Follow me on the way
Follow me, follow me, follow my heart
うーむむ うーむむ
Uh-mu-mu, uh-mu-mu
思うまま夢を描こう 描いて
Let's paint a dream as we please, let's paint it
願いがそのま欲しいがった
I've wished for my desires to stay as they are
描いた夜を越えていこう 越えていこう
Let's cross over the night we drew, let's go
このまま 光の向こう側へ
Just like this, to the other side of the light
追いかけて合わせた姿作って
Chase it, match it, create the figure
もういい人なんてやめない
I'm done being a good person
世界の向こう側へ
To the other side of the world
I've already started
Beyond the way
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、本日はこのお二人に来ていただきました！
And so, today, we have these two joining us!
イェーイ！
Yay!
来ました！
We're here!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あい、あい、あい！
Ayyy, ayy, ayy!
せーの、お誕生日おめでとう！
Ready, and... Happy birthday!
やったー！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much!
お忙しいのにお二人とも今日はね、てかずっとレッスンからか。本当にお付き合いいただきましてありがとうございます
I know you're both busy, but you came today, and even helped with lessons. Thank you for joining me.
こちらこそありがとうございます。
No, thank you!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
今回はですね、誕生日で実は衣装が…
For my birthday this time, I actually got a new outfit.
衣装が…
The outfit...
ストッキングかわいいでしょ？
Aren't the stockings cute?
おへそ、おへそ見えちる！
Your belly button is showing!
おへそ！やべ、取られる。
My belly button! Oh no, they'll steal it.
後ろかわいい！
The back is cute!
めっちゃかわいい！超似合ってる！似合ってる！
It looks so good on you!
そうなんです。新しくね、ダンスする用みたいなね衣装になったのでこれはおそれ多くも二人を呼ぼうかな。ダンスがうまいお二人を呼んでみてもいいかなって、呼ばせていただきました！
That's right! It's a new outfit made for dancing, so I thought, even if it's presumptuous, I'd invite you two skilled dancers.
え？
Eh?
違う…あなた、あなた方。
No, it's you two!
めっちゃ楽しかった！
That was so much fun!
楽しかった！
So fun!
レッスンもね、一緒に頑張っていただきまして
Yes, we practiced together and worked hard.
でも二人ともめちゃくちゃ元がうまいから風真一人だけどうしようかなこれ二人呼んで大丈夫だったかな
But you two are so naturally good, I was the only one thinking, "What should I do?" "Was it okay to invite them?"
めっちゃ踊った！
I really danced a lot!
最高のものができたと思います。
I think we created something amazing.
みんな、いいものできたよね？って、多分今頃コメントにはね、めっちゃよかったよーが流れてると思います。
Everyone, we made something good, right? I bet the comments are full of "That was great!" right now.
めちゃくちゃ嬉しい！
It was really fun!
だって、いろはちゃんと初めてじゃん。一緒にダンスするの。
Because it's my first time dancing with you, Iroha-chan.
そうなんですよ！
That's right!
こういうダンス、初めて。
This kind of dance, it's a first.
新衣装男子
New outfits!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しい。
I'm so happy.
いや、嬉しい。
I am, I'm happy.
いや、ほんと誘ってよかった。
I'm so glad I invited you.
よかった、うれしい。
I'm glad, I'm happy.
いや、二人と一緒にね、このね期間一緒に踊って
Dancing with you both during this period
めちゃくちゃ勉強になりました。先生方。
was a huge learning experience. My teachers.
ありがとう。そんなことないですよ。
Thank you. That's not true.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
あ、どうも。いや、もう本当に。
Oh, thank you. No, really.
え、またね何かあったらぜひ一緒に踊って！
If there's another chance, let's dance together!
やりたい！一緒にやりましょう！
I want to! Let's do it together!
やりましょう！
Let's do it!
いつでも呼んでください！
Call me anytime!
ぜひやりましょう。
Let's definitely do it.
じゃあ、ちょっとこの記念に、この友情の証
Okay, to commemorate this, as proof of our friendship,
強いかっこいいポーズで写真撮っとこう。
let's take a photo with a strong, cool pose.
かっこいいポーズ？かっこいいポーズ。
A cool pose? A cool pose.
かっこいいポーズ思いつかない。
I can't think of a cool pose.
なんだ？
What should we do?
What is it?
かわいい。
Cute.
かわいい。めっちゃかわいい。
Cute. So cute.
ま、いっか。
Oh well, this is fine.
みんなたくさんSNSに投稿してくださいね。
Everyone, please post lots on social media.
かっしゃい。
Click!
はい。と言いつつ、
Okay. Having said that,
実はですね、もう一つお願いがあって。
I actually have one more favor to ask.
おお？
Oh?
今日この後、今日初お披露目の
Later today, I'll be performing for the first time...
オリ曲があるんですけど。
...an original song of mine.
オリ曲？
An original song?
うわー！
Wooow!
楽しみ！楽しみだ！
I'm excited! I'm so excited!
どんな曲？
What kind of song?
やっぱり風真いろは、
As Kazama Iroha,
かっこよくなりたくて、今回は
I wanted to be cool, so this time,
かっこいい曲を持ってまいりました！
I've brought a cool song!
うわー！楽しみ！
Wow! I'm excited!
イッツクール！イェー！
It's cool! Yeah!
可愛くてかっこいいお二人から、
From you two who are cute and cool,
やっぱちょっと勇気をもらってから行こうかなと。
I thought I'd get some courage before I go.
かっこいいビーム。
Cool beam.
え？待って、もらった、かっこいいビーム、フワー！
Huh? Wait, I got it, the cool beam! Whoosh!
すごい！なんか、
Amazing! For some reason,
なんかちょっとイケメンになってきてる気がする。
I feel like I'm becoming a bit handsome.
ちょっと待ってイケメンのポーズ分かんない。こう？
Wait, I don't know a handsome pose. Like this?
いいよ、かっこいいじゃん。
Nice, that's cool.
わあ、うわあ。
Wow, wow.
え、イケてる気がする。
Hey, I feel like I'm cool.
イケてる！
You are!
いける！いける気がする！
I can do this! I feel like I can!
いいじゃん、いいじゃん。よし。
Nice, nice. Alright.
二人からめちゃくちゃエネルギーもらえたんで
I got so much energy from you two,
頑張ってきます！
so I'll do my best!
頑張って！いってらっしゃい！
Go for it! Do your best!
２人とも今日は本当に、お祝いと、そして、一緒に歌って踊ってくれて
To you both, thank you for the celebration and singing and dancing with me,
そして、この応援ビームをありがとうございました。
and thank you for that support beam.
こちらこそありがとうございます。
Thank you too.
また遊びましょうね。
Let's hang out again.
はい。
Yes.
じゃあ、それではこの後、新オリ曲を
Well then, after this, my new original song
初お披露目させていただきます。
will have its first premiere.
それでは、せーの、どうぞ！
And now, ready, set, go!
見た目だけじゃワカラナイ
You can't tell just by looking
ワタシのこと可愛いだけど
You may think I'm cute, but
まさか思っていないよね？
You couldn't possibly think... could you?
ワタシのホント
...about the real me.
知っていてほしいのに
I want you to know me,
ホントノワタシ
the real me.
Passion Passion Burning
Emotion Emotion
予測誤差の範囲と
The margin of error in predictions
不測の事態も動じない
and unforeseen events don't faze me.
おすましフェイスでいるけど
I wear a composed face, but
心は常に青白く燃える
my heart is always burning pale and blue.
諦めはしない
I won't give up,
媚びたりもしない
I won't flatter,
ワタシを曲げない
and I won't compromise myself.
扱いやすいヤツだと思うな
Don't you think I'm easy to handle?
甘く見ると痛い目みるぞ
Underestimate me and you'll get hurt.
それでもときには
But still, at times,
逃げ出してしまいたい
I just want to run away.
そんな衝動に
Driven by that kind of impulse,
弱音吐きたくなる真夜中もある
there are midnights I want to complain.
ほんの小さな小さな妥協が
Just one tiny, tiny compromise
積み重なり重なって動けない
piles up and up until I can't move.
大きな大きな可能性なくし
Losing out on huge possibilities,
未来を狭めてしまうから
I end up narrowing my own future.
どんなに暗くても辛くても後悔だけはしない
No matter how dark or painful, I'll never have regrets.
イケてるのは見た目じゃなくて
Being "cool" isn't about appearances,
生き方なんだ
it's about how you live.
現実と理想との距離を縮められたとしても
Even if I could close the gap between reality and my ideals,
おすましフェイスでいるだけ
I just wear a composed face,
何事もなかったかのように
as though nothing ever happened.
立ち止まりはしない
I won't stop.
後戻りもない
There's no turning back.
夢を捨てない
I won't abandon my dreams.
らしいとからしくないとか
"Acting like me" or "not like me"...
決めつけないで 全部がワタシ
don't label me. All of it is me.
それでもときには
But still, at times,
温もりが恋しい
I find myself longing for warmth.
そんな感情に
By those kinds of feelings,
流されてしまいそうな真夜中もある
there are midnights I might be swept away.
こんな甘い甘いことだけ
I don't need the weakness
求めてしまうような弱さいらない
of only ever seeking sweet things.
苦い苦い経験だって
Because even bitter, bitter experiences
ワタシを強くしてくれるから
will make me stronger.
これがこれがワタシの
This, this is my...
ホント
my true self.
とても狭い狭い世界の
In this very narrow, narrow world,
中だけで終わらせたくはないんだ
I don't want it all to end.
広い広い世界の
To the ends of this wide, wide world,
果てまで駆け抜けて生きてくんだから
I'll run through it all and live!
どんなに険しくて過酷でも
No matter how rugged or harsh,
楽しんでやるさ
I'm going to enjoy it!
イケてるのは
Being "cool"...
はい。というわけでみなさん。
Okay, so everyone.
ゲストパートから続けて、
Continuing on from the guest part,
新オリ曲「ホントノワタシ」
my new original song, "Honto no Watashi",
歌って踊らせていただきました。
I just sang and danced it for you.
なんと風真いろは、
Can you believe it, this is Kazama Iroha's
7曲目のオリ曲です！
seventh original song!
ちょっとオリ曲のジャケットも届いているので見ていきましょう。
The jacket art for the song has arrived, so let's see it.
こちらです！
Here it is!
こちらの風真いろは新オリ曲、7曲目、
This, Kazama Iroha's new, seventh original song,
「ホントノワタシ」は、こちら
"Honto no Watashi", will be released...
日付変わりまして、19日0時より
when the date changes, from 0:00 on the 19th.
リリースされることとなりました。
It's been decided that it will be released!
今回の新衣装にちなんで、こちら作っていただきました。
It was made to go along with my new outfit.
はい。ちょっと今までとだいぶ系統の違う曲になるんですけれども、
Yes. It's a song with a very different style than before,
あの、いつもみんなね、ありがたいことに風真いろはのこと
you know, everyone, I'm very grateful that you always...
「かっこいい」っていうよりも「かわいい」って言ってくださる方がいっぱいいるので、
say I'm 'cute' rather than 'cool'.
いや「かっこいいとこもあるんだよ」っていうのを伝えたくて作っていただきました。
So I had this made to show you I have a cool side too.
こちら、ぜひ0時にリリースされたらたくさん聞いて、
When it's released at midnight, please listen to it a lot.
また、ハッシュタグの見てみていろは殿で
And then, with the hashtag #MiteMiteIrohadono,
感想とか教えていただいたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you told me your thoughts.
そしてそして、ゲストパートについてもお話ししていきますかね。じゃ、戻って。
And also, shall we talk about the guest part? Okay, let's go back.
はい。ゲストでね、ミオ先輩と、
Yes. For the guests, I had Mio-senpai,
そして、はじめちゃんベイ先輩と
and also Hajime-chan and Bae-senpai.
一緒に歌って踊らせていただきました。
I had them sing and dance with me.
ミオ先輩、そしてベーね、そしてはじめちゃん、来てくれて、ありが、ありがとう！
Mio-senpai, and Bae, and Hajime-chan, thank you, thank you for coming!
もう本当に歌も難しかったし、
The song was really difficult,
もう、べ、ベーとはじめちゃんのやつに関しては、もうこれができなさすぎて、
and for the one with Bae and Hajime-chan, I was so bad at this part...
一生やりすぎて、あの、一生腰痛を抱えて、
I practiced it so much that I ended up with a backache.
これ、これが結構筋肉痛の原因でした。
This was pretty much the cause of my muscle soreness.
はい。でも、すごい一緒に歌って踊らせていただきまして、とってもとってもいい経験になりました。
Yes. But it was amazing to sing and dance together, it was a very good experience.
皆さん、ありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much!
じゃあ、次の曲に行く前に、お水飲んでいいですか？
So, before we go to the next song, may I drink some water?
お水飲みます。
I'm going to drink some water.
お水。ロゴも見て、実は変わってた。
Water. Look at the logo, it actually changed.
よし。
Alright.
お待たせしました。
Thank you for waiting.
息整えて。
Let me catch my breath.
はい。次の曲なんですけれども、
Yes. About the next song,
やっぱりみんなバラードも好きだよって言ってくれる方が多いので、
many of you say you like ballads, so...
今回の…
this time's...
生誕ライブ、バラードやろうと思って持ってきました。
For my birthday live, I decided to do a ballad.
はい。ちょっとかっこいい感じに歌えるか
Yes. I practiced a lot to see
色々練習したんですけど、
if I could sing it in a cool way.
ぜひ心を込めて歌うので、
I'll sing it with all my heart,
聞いていただけると嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you'd listen.
それでは、次の曲、お聞きください。
Well then, please listen to the next song.
W/X/Y
垂れ流した
The sound of the TV
テレビの音
that was left on.
溜めてしまった
The laundry that I've let pile up,
洗濯物は今日こそ
I'll do it today for sure.
晴れでも雨でも会えて
Whether it's sunny or rainy, let's meet up,
外には出ないでいよう
but let's not go outside.
映えないスナックと
With some plain snacks
アルコールで乾杯をしよう
and alcohol, let's make a toast.
2人酸いも甘いも噛み合わないとしても
Even if we don't mesh on the good and the bad,
お互い寄り添うように 少しずらしてみようよ
let's try to shift a little to get closer.
君がくれた太陽 月で隠れないよう
The sun you gave me, so the moon won't hide it,
輝き絶やさぬように 歌うメロディ
a melody sung so its shine never ends.
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Playing around, a slowly flowing day.
愛してるも通り越して
It's gone beyond "I love you."
似た者同士こうして
Two peas in a pod, like this,
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want to laugh until we're old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, I fall asleep in bed.
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby.
脱ぎっぱなしの
When I follow the trail of clothes
足跡辿ると
left on the floor,
不意をついて後ろから抱きつくの
you take me by surprise and hug me from behind.
つい、繰り返すと
If we keep doing this,
忘れてしまいそうになるよ
I feel like I might forget.
振り返ると
When I look back,
日々が当たり前じゃないこと
I see that these days aren't a given.
2人対の細胞 絡み合う特別を
The two of us, a pair of cells, a special bond,
噛み締めて生きたいと思った
I realized I want to cherish it and live.
まどろみ抱く正午 吐息漏れた体温
A sleepy embrace at noon, a sigh escapes with body heat.
1mmも逃さないように
I won't let even 1mm escape,
頭の中刻む甘いメモリー
engraving this sweet memory in my mind.
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Playing around, a slowly flowing day.
愛してるも通り越して
It's gone beyond "I love you."
違う者同士こうして
Two different people, like this,
年老いるまで
until we grow old.
年老いるまで 笑っていたいね
I wanna be laughing with you 'til we're old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In a dream, fall asleep in bed.
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
重ねた手はね離さないでいて
Don't let go of our held hands.
ごめん、これ、そばに居たいだけだね
Sorry, this is just me wanting to be by your side.
抱えた想いは お互い様でしょ
The feelings we hold, they're mutual, aren't they?
ほら、あいこでしょ
See? It's a draw.
すれ違い、間違いもあるし
We have misunderstandings and make mistakes.
筋書き通り行かない
Things don't go according to plan.
悲しみだって 半分こにしよう
Let's even share our sadness in half.
別れじゃない希望
It's not a farewell but a hope,
独りよがりにならないように、いつも
so I won't be selfish, always.
Whoa...
君がいなきゃ今もどこかで
Without you, even now, I'd be stuck somewhere,
動けないままの僕で
the same me who couldn't move.
ありがとうを伝えたいのです
I want to tell you "thank you".
これからは僕が支えてくって
From now on, I'll be the one to support you,
呆れてしまうくらいにね
to the point where you'd be amazed.
愛が増していく day by day
My love grows day by day.
面と向かうとどうしても
When we're face to face, I just can't be honest.
素直になれないな、ごめんね
I'm sorry about that.
ねえ
Hey.
戯れる Slowly flowing day
A playful, slowly flowing day.
愛してるも 通り越して
Going beyond even "I love you",
似た者同士 こうして
we're so alike, and like this,
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I wanna be laughing 'til we're old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In a dream, fall asleep in bed.
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
はい、それではですね、
Yes, and now...
皆さん、
everyone,
ここまで聞いていただきまして、本当にありがとうございます。
thank you so much for listening up to this point.
こんなに…ちょっと歌わせていただいたんですけども、
I got to sing a song like this... but
バラードなかなか3Dライブでやらないので、すごく緊張しました。
I don't often do ballads in 3D lives, so I was really nervous.
どうだったでしょうか？
How was it?
わ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ拍手と「めっちゃいい」っていうやつが見える。
Wow, I can see so much applause and "that was great" comments.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
そして、ここで、皆さんお待ちかねの、あの告知を挟ませていただければと思います。
And now, I'd like to make that long-awaited announcement for all of you.
それでは元気に行きます！
Alright, let's do this with energy!
それでは、どん！風真いろは、2025誕生日記念グッズ！
Here it is! Kazama Iroha's 2025 Birthday Anniversary merchandise!
出ます！イエーイ！
It's out! Yay!
ビジュアルが大変よろし。
The visual is very nice.
こちらのグッズが販売決定です。
These goods have been confirmed for sale.
はい、というわけで詳細を見ていきましょう。どん。
Yes, so let's look at the details. Boom.
はい、まず一つ目は、回転アクリルスタンド。
Yes, first up is the rotating acrylic stand.
え、イラストはナルダク先生に描いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Nardack-sensei.
うわー！
Wow!
こちらですね、あの、こういうことです。
This one, well, it's like this.
あの、あの、裏表になってるって言いたい。
Um, um, what I mean is it's double-sided.
裏、裏表になってる。そう、あの
Front and back. Yes, um...
カラーライズ衣装とこの新しい新衣装で裏表になってます。
It's double-sided with the Colorize outfit and this new outfit.
くるくる回せるので、あの
You can spin it around, so...
ござるのこと回して遊んでください。よろしくお願いします。
Please spin me around and have fun with it. Thank you very much.
そして、次がこちら。
And next up is this.
はい。温感湯呑み。
Yes. A heat-sensitive teacup.
これ、ついさっき、サンプルが控え室に届いて試しました。
I just tried this. A sample arrived in the waiting room a little while ago.
あの、ちゃんとあったかいの入れるとふわーってですね、
If you put something hot in it, it appears gradually,
ちゃんとポコべが浮き出て、ござるが打ち合わせとかね、
Pokobee appears properly. While I was in a meeting...
あの、リハやってる間に湯が冷めきってちゃんと緑に戻っておりました。
or a rehearsal, the water cooled down and it turned back to green.
こちらもすごく可愛くてお寿司屋さんとかにあるサイズなのかな？
This is also very cute. Is it the size you find at a sushi place?
結構大きめのちゃんとした湯呑みです。ぜひね、使ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
It's a proper, fairly large teacup. I'd love it if you used it.
はい。そして次がこちら。
Yes. And next is this.
はい、風真いろは、新、こちらポップダンス衣装って名前なんですけど、
Yes, it's a Kazama Iroha new... this is called the Pop Dance outfit,
のぬいぐるみです。
but it's a plushie.
ぜひお迎えして欲しいな。
I'd really like you to get one.
ござるさんのぬいぐるみでみんな遊んでくれ。
Please play with Gozaru's plushie, everyone.
っていうことで、このツインテールのね、新衣装、なんとぬいぐるみになりました。
So, this new twintail outfit has become a plushie.
あの、手持ちじゃなくて、こう、こういうタイプだったかな？
Um, it's not handheld, it's more... this type, I think?
だと思うので、ぜひね、みんなのおうちにかざってもらえたら嬉しいです。
So, I'd be happy if you all displayed it in your homes.
そして、次はこちら。
And next up is this.
はい。なんとござるのこれ、
Yes! Amazingly, Gozaru's... this!
これとお揃いのこれが出ます。
A matching version of this is coming out.
ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、もう一回やり直していい？
Wait, wait, wait, can I do that over?
これとお揃いのネックレスが出ます。
A matching necklace to this is coming out.
で、普段ね、アクセサリーとかつけない隊士さんね、つけないよって方も
For the troopers who don't usually wear accessories,
ま、よかったらこちらね、あのさっきのぬいぐるみにあのくくって一緒にセットにして飾っていただいたりとか
if you like, you can attach this to the plushie from earlier and display them as a set,
イベントの時につけてきてもらえたら嬉しいです。おしゃれです。
or wear it to events. I'd be happy either way. It's stylish.
ござると一緒に、お揃いによかったらしましょう。
If you'd like, let's match with Gozaru.
というわけで、そしてフルセットがこんな感じ？
So, with that said, the full set looks something like this?
うわあ。なんだか爽やかですね。
Wow. It's somehow very refreshing.
そう、ライブタイトルの通りリバーシブルなんで、色々ちょっと反転、反転がついてたりします。
Yes, just like the live title, it's 'Reversible', so various things are inverted.
そして、購入特典はこちら！
And the purchase bonus is this!
この戦争を終わらせに来ました。
I've come to end this war.
今回はですね、グッズが２種類出るということで、
This time, since there are two types of merch,
数量限定はせずに、ちょっと変わった特典にしてみました。
we decided against a limited quantity and went for a unique bonus.
こちらは裏表のタロットカードが付いてきます。
This comes with a double-sided tarot card.
片面には風真の、えっと、複製サインとメッセージが入っております。
On one side, there's Kazama's printed sign and a message.
こちらもね、こう裏表で
This is also double-sided.
楽しんでいただけたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you enjoyed it.
数量限定とかではないので
It's not a limited quantity item,
ゆっくりね、あの、購入していただければと思います。
so please take your time when purchasing.
販売開始時間がこの後21時なんですけど、
Sales start at 9 PM after this,
ちょっと生配信の関係上、ちょっと生配信伸びる可能性のが今大なので、
but due to the livestream, it's very likely to run long,
生配信中に皆さん、あの、カート見に行ってください。
so everyone, please go check the cart during the stream.
あ、でもあの、数量限定とかないので、安心してください。
Oh, but it's not limited in quantity, so please don't worry.
はい。そして、フルセットの特典もう一つあります。
Yes. And there's one more bonus for the full set.
こちらです。
Here it is.
はい。みんな大好きホロカのカードが
Yes! Everyone's favorite Holoka card
1枚付いてきます。
is included!
はい、皆さんよかったらお手に取って
Yes, everyone, if you'd like, please get one.
ホロカ勢の皆さんは使ってくださいね。
And to all you Holoka players, please use it.
遊び方とか、あとカードの詳細は
For how to play and more details on the card,
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの公式ホームページにてご確認ください。
please check the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME official website.
よし。今、台本めっちゃ見た。
Okay. I was staring at the script just now.
言えなかったらやばいと思って。
I thought it'd be bad if I messed it up.
そして、こちら、一緒に入れさせていただくカードは、日本語版のみとなっておりますので、
And the card that's included with this is the Japanese version only,
ご両所ください。
so please be aware of that.
はい。
Yes.
カートのオープンですが、こちらですね、100万人記念グッズと誕生日記念グッズ、
The cart will open for both the 1 million sub commemorative goods
両方同時なので、皆さんよろしくお願いします。
and the birthday goods at the same time, so please check them out.
ちょっと、ごめんなさい、生配信押しちゃってごめんね。
I'm sorry, I'm sorry the stream is running long.
ホロメンも、ホロメンも配信を推してすみません。
To the Holo-members too, sorry for the long stream.
はい。というわけで、ちょっとお水飲みます。
Right. With that said, I'm going to have some water.
（ため息）
(Sighs)
というわけで、あと最後の、お知らせとしまして、
And so, for the final announcement,
この後、本編終了次第、ちょっとまた時間がね、確定しな、15分からか20分からかどっちかになると思うんですけど、
after the main part ends, it'll be 15 or 20 minutes later, I think,
風真いろはのメンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブもございますので、
there will be a members-only encore live,
皆が見たかったあの曲やこの曲を歌ったり踊ったりしますので、
I'll be singing and dancing to that song that everyone wanted to see,
よかったら見に来てください。
so please come and watch if you'd like.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
メンバーシップギフトとか、今日から入ってくださった隊士さんもありがとうございます。
Thank you to those who gifted memberships, and the Troopers who joined today.
はい。そして、なんと残念なことに、次の曲が、皆さん、
Yes. And unfortunately, everyone, the next song
このライブ最後の曲となります。
will be the last song of this live.
えー、皆さん、もう最後は何を歌うか、ある程度予想されている方も多いかと思いますが、
Um, I think many of you have already guessed what the last song will be,
改めまして、この度は、風真いろは生誕LIVE 2025、
but once again, for Kazama Iroha's Birthday Live 2025,
お越しくださいまして、本当にありがとうございました。
thank you so much for coming.
そして、あの、制作のために一生懸命頑張ってくださったスタッフさんや、ダンスの先生やマネージャーさんや、
And to the staff who worked so hard to produce this, the dance teacher, my manager,
皆さん、本当に、クリエイターの皆さんも、ありがとうございました。
and all the creators, thank you so much.
あの、正直、色々あった昨年の年末から、
Honestly, after everything that happened since the end of last year,
ここまで声が戻って、ライブができるっていうことが、ほぼ奇跡、
for my voice to recover to this point and be able to do a live is almost a miracle.
なんだったら、もう半分諦めかけていた...
In fact, I had half given up...
いたんですけども、スタッフの皆さんや
but all the staff members and
ファンの隊士さんたちがすごい支えてくださって
all of you fans have been so supportive,
いろんな方に支えられて本日実施することができました。
and thanks to all of you, I was able to hold this event today.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you all so very much.
正直まだまだ本調子じゃない部分が
To be honest, there are still many parts of me
多いのは正直なところです。
that aren't in the best condition.
だけど今日少しでもこのライブを見て、たくさんの人に
But I hope that by watching this concert today,
元気が一人でも多く届いていればなと思っております。
I was able to bring energy to as many of you as possible.
これからもリハビリしながらですが、
I'll be continuing my rehabilitation,
精一杯頑張って参りますので、
but I will keep doing my absolute best,
皆さんこれからもよろしくお願いします。
so please continue to support me.
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、最後の曲にふさわしいこの曲、
And with that, here is a song fitting for the finale.
皆さん最後に聞いてください。
Everyone, please listen to this last song.
風真いろは新オリ曲
Kazama Iroha's new original song,
「君にしか読めない手紙」
"A Letter Only You Can Read."
ありがとう 書くとしたら
If I were to write "thank you,"
毎日になっちゃうくらい
it'd be something I'd do every day.
重すぎる 私の想いは
These heavy feelings of mine,
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the very end.
拝啓
Dear you,
私を形作った君へ
the one who shaped me.
相も変わらず言葉を
As always, my words,
届け続けています
I continue to deliver.
拝啓 未来で
Dear you, in the future,
私待ってる君へ
who's waiting for me.
響く音に 憂いなど
To the echoing sound, with no worries,
なく お過ごしでしょうか？
are you spending your summer?
不安が無い日なんて
A day without anxiety
多分無かったけど
probably never existed, but
私の言葉 君の言葉
My words, your words,
重なって笑えたんだ
overlapped and I could smile.
ありがとう 書くとしたら
If I were to write "thank you,"
毎日になっちゃうくらい
it'd be something I'd do every day.
重すぎる 私の想いは
These heavy feelings of mine,
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the very end.
君がいる それだけでさ
Just the fact you're here,
理由になるなんて奇跡
that it's a reason, is a miracle.
ありがとう 足りないのごまかすよ
"Thank you" isn't enough, so I'll cover it up with
愛してる
I love you.
魔法石のブレスレット
A magic stone bracelet,
シロツメクサの女王様
the queen of white clover.
プラスチックだらけの宝石箱で
In a jewelry box full of plastic,
ずっと遊べるよ君と
I can play with you forever.
思い出の欠片たち
Fragments of memories
溢れるこの場所で
overflow in this place.
私の言葉 君の言葉
My words, your words,
重ねて笑ってた
overlapped and we were smiling.
忘れられる世界で今
In a world where things can be forgotten,
私が選んだ生き方
this is the life I have chosen.
手紙をさ 書いたからさ
I wrote a letter, so
この音に乗せて
I'll send it with this sound.
ありがとう 書くとしたら
If I were to write 'Thank you,'
毎日になっちゃうくらい
it would become a daily thing.
重すぎる私の想いは
My feelings are too heavy,
最後に伝えるね
so I'll tell you at the end.
君がいる それだけでさ
Just having you here,
理由になるなんて奇跡
for that to be my reason, is a miracle.
ありがとう 足りないの
"Thank you" isn't enough,
誤魔化すよ
so I'll just say it:
愛してる
I love you.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!